Guide to the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 1289 (Seattle, Washington) Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 1289 records
1911-1958
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1227
1227-001
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.$bLocal 1289 (Seattle, Wash.)
64 cubic feet
Records of a trade union organization of Seattle, Washington
Trade union organization. Local 1289 is a Seattle affiliate of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.
Correspondence, 1920-1946; financial records and ephemera, 1911-1951.
Also includes papers of the Central Labor council of Seattle and Vicinity, 1923-1930; Seattle Building Trades Council, 1923-1944; and Washington State Council of United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, 1922-1958.
Access restricted: For terms of access contact repository.
Merlin C. Brown, Secretary, Carpenters Local 1289, UBC and Joiners of America, Seattle;, September 10, 1969
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.$bLocal 1289 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; Carpenters$zWashington (State); Woodworkers$zWashington (State); Carpenters$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); Woodworkers$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); Building trades$zWashington (State); Building trades$xEmployees$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); Central Labor Council of Seattle and Vicinity; Seattle Building Trades Council; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.$bWashington State Council; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Washington (State); Seattle
- Building Trades Council, Seattle, 1922-1945; Subgroup A (Box-folder 1/1-1/7)
  - MINUTES, 1922-1930; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/4)
    - Minutes, 1922 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Minutes, 1923 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Minutes, 1930 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Minutes, 1924 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1944; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Wage Scale, 1944 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1924, 1940; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Agreements, 1924, 1940 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - RESOLUTIONS, 1923; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Resolutions, 1923, 1945 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Carpenters District Council of Seattle and Vicinity, 1922-1945; Subgroup B (Box-folder 1/8-2/3)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, Undated; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Trade Rules, Undated (Box-folder 1/8)
  - RESOLUTIONS, 1922; SERIES II (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Resolutions, 1922 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Carpenters, Local 1289, 1911-1948; Subgroup C (Box-folder 2/4-11/21)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1922-1944; SERIES I (Box-folder 2/4-2/5)
    - Bylaws, c. 1920s (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Joint Council of City Employees Bylaws, c. 1920s-1944 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE - Incoming Letters, 1922-1948; SERIES II (Box-folder 2/6-3/5)
    - American Federation of Labor, 1922-1945 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - American Red Cross, Seattle King Co. Chapter, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Bone, Homer T., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Building Service Employees' International, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Building Trades Council, Seattle, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Carpenters, District Council of Seattle and Vicinity, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Carpenters, Various District Councils, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Carpenters, United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, 1922-1940 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Carpenters, United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Carpenters, United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, Various Locals, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Carpenters, Washington State Council of, 1924-1945 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Carpenters, Washington State Council of, Undated (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Central Labor Council of Seattle and Vicinity, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Daniels and Brinton, West Seattle Undertakers, 1923, 1941 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - De Lacy, Hugh, 1946 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Electrical Workers, International Brotherhood of, 1924, 1945 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Farmer Labor Party, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Friends of Soviet Russia, 1922 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Furniture Workers, Unions 1506 and 1719, 1940 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - General Defense Committee (Centrailia I.W.W. Defense), 1924 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Machinists, International Association of, Undated-1946 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Magnuson, Warren G., 1942-1946 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Salvation Army, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Seattle Labor College, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Seattle Muncipal Defense Commission, 1942 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Seattle Union Record, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - State Power Conference, 1924 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - U.S. Labor Department, Office of Price Administration, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - U.S. Treasury Department, 1922, 1945 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Wallgren, Senator Mon C., 1942-1944 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor - Building and Construction Trades Section, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Miscellaneous A-D, 1923-1944 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Miscellaneous E-K, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Miscellaneous L-N, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Miscellaneous P-S, 1940-1948 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Miscellaneous T-Y, 1922-1945 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE - Outgoing Letters, 1924, 1948; SERIES III (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Outgoing Letters (Box-folder 3/6)
  - CORRESPONDENCE - Interoffice, 1924-1946; SERIES IV (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Interoffice Letters (Box-folder 3/7)
  - MINUTES, 1911-1946; SERIES V (Box-folder 3/8-5/6)
    - Minutes (Journal), 1911-1912 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Minutes (Journal), 1913-1915 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Minutes (Journal), 1915-1919 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Minutes (Journal), 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Minutes (Journal), 1920-1923 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Minutes, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Minutes, 1927 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Minutes, 1928 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Minutes, 1929 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Minutes, 1930 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Minutes, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Minutes, 1934 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Minutes, 1935 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Minutes, 1936 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Minutes, 1937 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Minutes, 1938 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Minutes, 1939 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Minutes, 1940 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Minutes, 1941 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Minutes, 1942 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Minutes, 1943 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Minutes, 1944 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Minutes - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1910-1947; SERIES VI (Box-folder 5/7-8/9)
    - Bank book (West Seattle State Bank), 1918-1924 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Bank Resolutions and certificates for association, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Expenditures, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1910-1916 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1916-1921 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1921-1925 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1926-1930 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Expenditures and Income, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Financial Statements, 1922-1944 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Income Tax Returns, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Receipts, Bank (Safety deposit box), 1938-1942 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Receipts, Building Operations, 1939-1944 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Receipts, Carpenters, District Council, 1932-1944 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Receipts, Carpenters, United Brotherhood, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Receipts, Carpenters, Washington State Council, 1932-1944 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Receipts, Financial Secretary, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Receipts, Miscellany, 1923-1939 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1919 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1930 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1938 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1941 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1942 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1943 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1944 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1945 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1946 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Reports, Monthly Financial, 1947 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Sick Benefits, 1940-1947 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Sick Benefits, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Social Security Reports, 1936-1941 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Tax Statement, Real Estate, 1929-1940 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Treasurer's Notice, City of Seattle, 1931-1935 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Trustee's Report (Semi-Annual), 1921-1936 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Wage Scale, Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor, Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1921-1943 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - MEMBERSHIP, 1911-1944; SERIES VII (Box-folder 8/10-10/7)
    - Membership Records, 1911 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Membership Records, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Membership Records, 1919 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Membership Records, 1920 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Membership Records, 1923 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Membership Records, 1924 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Membership Records, 1925 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Membership Records, 1926 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Membership Records, 1927 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Membership Records, 1928 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Membership Records, 1929 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Membership Records, 1930 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Membership Records, 1931 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Membership Records, 1932 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Membership Records, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Membership Records, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Membership Records, 1938 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Membership Records, 1939 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Membership Records, 1942 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Membership Records, 1943 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Membership Records, 1944 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - CLEARANCE CARDS, 1942-1951; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 10/8-11/1)
    - Clearance Cards, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Clearance Cards, 1944-1951 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Members called to Military Service, Undated (Box-folder 11/1)
  - LEGAL DOCUMENTS, Undated; SERIES IX (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Agreements, Undated (Box-folder 11/2)
  - REPORTS, 1942-1945; SERIES X (Box-folder 11/3-11/4)
    - Committee Reports, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1943; SERIES XI (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - NEWS RELEASES, 1943; SERIES XII (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - CLIPPINGS, 1954; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Seattle Post-Intelligencer (Pg 3-4), 1954 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - LEGISLATION, 1938-1946; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 11/8-11/11)
    - Executive Order 9240, 1942 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Initiative 198 "Right to Work", 1947 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Voluntary Labor Stablization Plan, 1943 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1938-1946 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - ELECTIONS, 1924-1945; SERIES XV (Box-folder 11/12-11/15)
    - Ballots, 1943 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Campaign Material, c.1940s (Box-folder 11/13)
    - General Elections, 1924 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor: Run-Off Election Laws, 1945 (Box-folder 11/15)
  - CONVENTIONS, 1957-1958; SERIES XVI (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor and Washington State Building and Construction Trades Council, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - EPHEMERA, 1923-1946; SERIES XVII (Box-folder 11/17-11/19)
    - Carpenters United Brotherhood Circulars, 1922-1945 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Shops Fair to Labor lists, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1923-1946 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - EPHEMERA, 1941-1946; SERIES XVII (Box-folder 11/20-11/21)
    - Resolutions, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-1946 (Box-folder 11/21)
- Carpenters, Washington State Council of, 1922-1958; Subgroup D (Box-folder 11/22-12/9)
  - ORGANIZATION, Undated; SERIES I (Box-folder 11/22-11/23)
    - Constitution, Undated (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Constitutional Revisions, Undated (Box-folder 11/23)
  - MINUTES, 1942-1943; SERIES II (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Board Meeting, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 11/24)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1922; SERIES III (Box-folder 11/25)
    - Receipts and Expenses, 1922 (Box-folder 11/25)
  - MEMBERSHIP, 1945; SERIES IV (Box-folder 11/26)
    - Delinquent Dues, 1945 (Box-folder 11/26)
  - LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1945; SERIES V (Box-folder 11/27)
    - Western Washington Heavy Construction Agreement, 1945 (Box-folder 11/27)
  - REPORTS, 1940-1946; SERIES VI (Box-folder 11/28-11/32)
    - President's Financial and Activity Reports, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - President's Financial and Activity Reports, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 11/29)
    - President's Financial and Activity Reports, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 11/30)
    - Shipbuilding and Zoning Conference, 1944 (Box-folder 11/31)
    - Western Washington Heavy Construction Agreement, 1945 (Box-folder 11/32)
  - NEWS RELEASES, 1944; SERIES VII (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Office of War Information, 1944 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - LEGISLATION, 1922; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Referendum, 1922 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - CONVENTIONS, 1939; SERIES IX (Box-folder 12/3-12/4)
    - Convention Proceedings, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Convention Proceedings, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - EPHEMERA, 1953-1958; SERIES X (Box-folder 12/5-12/8)
    - State Labor Directory Yearbook, 1953 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - State Labor Directory Yearbook, 1955 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - State Labor Directory Yearbook, 1956 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - State Labor Directory Yearbook, 1958 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - MISCELLANY, 1942-1946; SERIES VI (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Resolutions, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 12/9)
- Seattle Central Labor Council, 1923-1930; Subgroup E (Box-folder 12/10-12/14)
  - MINUTES, 1923-1930; SERIES I (Box-folder 12/10-12/12)
    - Minutes, 1923 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Minutes, 1924 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Minutes, 1930 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - REPORTS, Undated; SERIES II (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Political Welfare Committee, Undated (Box-folder 12/13)
  - MISCELLANY, 1923-1924; SERIES III (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Unfair Lists, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 12/14)